HANIYEH FATHOLAHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: haniyeh.fath@gmail.com

Address: Dortmund, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/h-fatholahi



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with 5 years of work experience in medium-sized and large companies providing software solutions in the fields of intelligent transportation, fleet tracking, payment and insurance systems. Also, I am skilled in system analysis, design and backend development.

my expertise is developed applications and APIs using Java and NodeJS including their related frameworks, technologies and tools like different databases - SQL and NoSQL databases. In addition, experienced in developed services for IoT devices such as management and communication services.

EXPERIENCES

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

JAVA DEVELOPER IN INSURANCE CORE INSURANCE, <u>DOTIN</u>, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Contributed to design and develop the system new service, legal insurance
- Designed and implemented legal insurance rest APIs
- Refactored 100% of the code for annual insurance branch performance report in order to increase reusability
- Refactored several financial features in order to improve performance and reusability
- Designed and implemented marketers reporting dashboard
- Improved WebSocket notification service memory consumption by tunning the configuration and refactoring the code

OCT 2016 - FEB 2021

R&D DEPARTMENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAGFA, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Developed fleet tracking services for GPS tracking systems containing about 3000 online tracker devices
- Optimized performance by using multithreading and queuing
- Designed and implemented Rest APIs for fleet tracking applications and services
- Collaborated with Frontend team in order to upgrade frontend technologies
- Designed and developed a USSD Wrapper service for USSD based mobile payments

SEP 2016 – MAR 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TOOBATECH, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Technical lead of Toobatel Instant messaging system project for Alzahra university
- Designed and implemented 100% chatting system in Toobatel app
- Designed and implemented Toobatel bot engine in order to integrate student services
- Designed and implemented backend services based on customers' requirement

SKILLS

	Solid Understanding	Worked With	Familiar with Or Intrigued by
Programming .	- Java	- JavaScript	- Typescript
languages	- NodeJS	- Python	0 "
Development tools/frameworks	SpringSpring BootHibernateExpress JSJSFMaven	- JPA - Swagger	- Gradle
Software engineering & methodologies	OOPAgileScrumSystem designDebug and Tshoot	Design PatternsGITCI/CDUnit TestingDDD	
Architecture	MicroserviceMVC	- SOA	
Web technologies	 RESTful APIs SOAP Webservices JSON HTTP JSP/Servlet Socket programming 	- JWT - jUnit	
IDEs and tools	 IntelliJ idea Netbeans Eclipse Webstorm Postman iReport SQL developer argoUML 	 Docker Apache tomcat verneMQ RabbitMQ Apache webserver Nginx jConsole jMeter 	 Kubernetes Jenkins Kafka Ansible
Databases	OracleMySQLMongoDBRedis	Neo4jPostgreSQLCassandra	
OS	- Windows - CentOS	- Ubuntu	
Project/Source control tools	GitLabBitBucketRedmineJira	- Trello	

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, ALZAHRA UNIVERSITY,

TEHRAN

Dissertation Title: "implementing IoT platform by customizing Openstack cloud computing Infrastructure APIs for collecting metrics from IoT nodes. "

CERTIFICATES

- Oracle Database 12c administration, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran
- Java 8 Standard Edition, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran

LANGUAGES

• Persian: Native

English: Fluent (TOEFL iBT certificate – C2)
 German: Basic (taking in A2 level classes)